CHEYO KAPELANSHILA CHOMBA

GRADUATE CONSULTANT



CONTACT (+27) 73 607 6938

kapelanshila@gmail.com

18 Platboom Avenue Weltervreden Park

https://github.com/Kapelanshila

EDUCATION

University of Pretoria

(BIS) Information Science 2020 - 2022

Main Subjects: Informatics (Information Systems) and Information Science

(BITHons) Information Systems 2022 - 2023

Main Subjects: Data Warehousing, Enterprise Architecture, Applied Data Science, Information Systems Development, Management of ICT Projects, Management of Information

Systems

SKILLS

- Communication Skills
- Diligence
- Analytical Skills
- Active Listening
- Creativity
- Critical Thinking

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- C#
- .NET
- Typescript
- Angular
- Ionic
- Python

PROFILE

I have completed my three-year BIS (Information Science) Degree at the University of Pretoria focusing on Information Systems and I have also completed my post-graduate studies for Honours in Information Systems. I have always been interested in technology and work on digital art in my spare time. My goal is to design efficient IT systems and solutions and implement and create visually appealing and easy-to-use systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior IT Specialist

Dataproof Communications (Pty) Ltd.

2021 - 2023

Responsibilities

- Data Capturing: Capturing of metadata information from spreadsheets that I
 developed under supervision into the Dataproof proprietary records
 management system used for archiving public records according to a National
 Archives of South Africa (NARS) approved File Plans.
- Data Auditing: Auditing uploaded information in the records management system to ensure that the scanned physical documents, metadata and compliance with the approved file plans are correct and accurate.
- Code Analysis: Analysis of the Dataproof proprietary records management system code and structure and advising on consistent improvements to features, efficiency and general architecture of the solution.
- Business Analysis: Synopsis assessment of Dataproof records management division operations and contributing to how technology can optimise the operations of the business.

Graduate Consultant (Data Engineering)

Moyo Business Advisory

2024 - Current

Company Core Business

Digital Consulting, Technology Solutions, Talent Solutions, Engineering

PROJECTS

University Final Year Project

My final year university project involved developing a system for a client in team of five. The designed system was a asset management, order management and procurement system. This took place over the course of a year where I was the lead developer.

GitHub Code

https://github.com/Kapelanshila/Team-1-Ventrix.git

Languages

• Typescript, C#, SQL, CSS

Frameworks

• Angular, Ionic , Net Framework

Deployment Tools

Microsoft Azure